So for 2026,
I've got several revenue streams.
We're going to go through them,
what they make, how they make it,
what they cost.
Pick a business. Which one
are you curious about first?
Business mentorship.
So this channel technically
is the IP of business
mentorship.
The only reason this channel exists
is to fuel this business.
Now,
what would be the first thing you want to
know about it? Revenue? Oh.
I mean, some months
are bigger than others, let's have a look.
Oh,
you want to go straight in for the good
juices, don't you?
Man wants to know profit straight away.
The thing we are guilty of in this
is saying revenue as if it's profit
when it's
just not the case.
So we started this two years ago.
4.4 million USD,
which you could say averages a month.
Well, actually,
what's 4.4 million divided by 24?
Give or take 183K a month US dollars,
which is all right.
Out of what I get to keep after ads
and after costs, everything else, about
55%. Of which then Luke, my manager,
gets his 20%
roughly. So let's bump that down.
Let's say luckily, maybe 40%.
However, I reinvest quite a lot of
that quite heavily.
The amount I actually take out
is quite a bit less than that.
So the way that we market this,
we have this YouTube channel.
We have its own Instagram page.
Interestingly, this YouTube channel and my
podcast, which we'll get into in a second,
are kind of fighting for positions.
We have staff, some of which
are outsourced to a company that
we use, and then in-house would be Declan,
me, Ollie.
Ollie is a little YouTube boffin
that we found in the UK, and he's
currently doing some work in the
mentorship as well.
So those of you in the Discord will see
Ollie in there.
As far as deliverables
or what the business mentorship is, it
is lots of courses
on content creation, editing,
email marketing, pricing,
branding, all of those things.
Those courses get built out all the time.
So for instance,
any of you in the mentorship right now,
there is a brand new
YouTube course coming out in the next few
days.
It'll be added to your account
automatically, so do get into it.
We spent a long time filming it
and getting it ready.
You're going to love it.
Those of you that have bought Short Form
Content Mastery or the
Black Belt Content Mastery,
that's getting completely swapped out.
You and I are going to film
that again next week.
So once people join,
they get a lifetime membership.
At the moment, I think it's about give
or take 3,000 US dollars
once-off payment once you're in.
And as far as deliverables, the main way
that I communicate people is in a Discord.
So they get access to me.
Cam is one of our marketing weapons,
and Ollie.
Because if you wanted to jump on a call
with me, it'd be extortionate.
For an hour, and we chat about a lot.
I give people the ability to just ask me
questions.
"Hey, James,
check out my squeeze page." I'll be like,
"Change that.
Doesn't look good enough." "What do you
think of this video?
Pay off too early," et cetera.
So business mentorship,
let's call it 2 million a
year. Lovely. I love this.
I do want to scale this.
In my mind,
I'd love to take the YouTube to 100K in
the next six months.
The way I see it,
if we double the amount of people at the
top end of the funnel,
we should double revenue. Scaling this
is going to be quite difficult because I
am
so involved. But even if this
was to get to 5 million US dollars a year,
I'm
happy with that.
Considering we've only got three members
of staff and an external
team, I don't think that's bad.
I think Brian Mark was saying he's got 40
or 50 staff or whatever.
I'd rather be poorer.
Okay, so we'll park that for the second.
Next business. Training app. Okay.
JSA.
So this bad boy's been going eight years.
I would say easily 125,000 people as far
as paid clients.
A lot of people say, oh,
we've had 600,000 members.
We could say that because they've created
an account, but they've not been paid
customers. Now, this one
is what I would call a lifestyle business.
Now, for many of you that
are in the fitness industry watching this,
you'll think
Adam Sullivan, you'll think Kayla Itsines,
you will think Joe Wicks, and you'll
think that you'll be...
And I say this because I did once in a
while.
You think that this
is going to be a massive
multimillion-dollar empire.
But the reality is, for this, two owners,
me and the other James, probably
got five staff.
And then my salary for this,
I do in pounds.
Call it 170K a year, take as a salary.
So we get dividends on top of that,
but the divs come as business
performance. 170K for me
is enough to live on.
That pays for almost everything.
So even without the mentorship,
I can still live
off of this. This is great, but it's nice.
This pays down my pension
and everything like that.
The dividends are on business performance,
so if we have a good week, there's more
in the payslip afterwards.
But there's been times
that I've been really frustrated
with this business, I'll be honest,
and there's times
that I've fallen out of love
with it, and people can see that online.
And the reality is, with this,
I need to spend hours
and hours a day in the Discord
helping people. This
is a very full-on business.
And this one,
although I've fallen out of love with it
quite a few times, and
there's been periods I've been motivated,
not motivated.
People watching this have probably seen
that.
It's actually a very cushy business where
although we don't
make tens of millions of dollars a year,
we have a tight member base that love the
app.
A lot of people stay on there long term.
And because we're quite a tight-knit
group, there's no stress,
there's no staff,
there's no waking up like, "Oh my God,
what are we going to do?
We've had a crisis." So what I would say
to people, this is my first
business.
This is the one where I've learned the
majority of the lessons.
When you want to scale a business,
as we'll talk about in Nutonic, stress,
headaches, staff, hiring. But
when you're making a couple of mil a year
and your
costs are pretty predictable
and your member base is pretty loyal
and there's not many complexities to it,
I'm never in here really
complaining about JSA.
I complain about other James sometimes
who's being
passive-aggressive. But
when I sit back and realize
that my fitness business is a
lifestyle business,
it's never going to buy me a private jet,
but it's going to pay
for me to fly business class.
It's never going to buy me a mansion,
but it's going
to put me in a three-bed house on the
beach. You know what I mean?
So
many people can get deflated thinking
that their business needs to be massive.
But really, I enjoyed this.
I lived sensibly,
and it's all the lessons
that I learned from that that got me this.
So the reason that I'm doing multiple
seven figures a year is because I
was happy
with just doing seven figures a year.
That makes sense.
Also, everything I teach here
is through running this for eight years
and a few
other things. Nutonic. So Nutonic
is not a lifestyle business.
Show them the fridge. How good's that?
So Nutonic at the moment
is doing 1 million plus
per month. So a million dollars a month,
which is pretty crazy.
In stock,
I'm pretty sure we've got $3 million,
if not more,
in stock. Profit, there is none.
Because the benefit or the thing
we're trying to do with this business
is to grow it.
So if you sell a can
or a pack of cans for 100 bucks
and you make
$20 profit,
that $20 goes straight into producing more
stock, going into more
territories, hiring more staff,
going into retail.
So we've launched a challenge For JSA,
money's in the bank.
I can spend it next month.
We have a good Black Friday for business
mentorship.
Money's in the bank. Nutonic,
my net position is probably
minus probably 300,000, maybe more.
I actually don't know.
I'll have to ask my manager.
Because my business partner, Luke,
he has all my money.
He pretty much just keeps hold of it
and says, "Oh, by the way,
we've just invested
in this." He told me the other day, "Oh,
I've just invested in two more businesses
on your behalf." I was like,
"Cheers." So this is anything
but a lifestyle
business.
This is something where you're putting out
fires all the time.
Raises, dilutions. It's stressful.
If I wake up and there's a shitty email
marketing email that's gone out, this
project depends,
the rest of our life depends on this
decking.
Whether you're flying in economy,
business, or on a jet is down to this.
Where your kids go to school
is based on this decking.
What house my kids grow up in
is based on this. This, not so much.
This, if we can grow this,
I'll upgrade you to business a few more
times.
But that's the big play.
This either does so much
better than you could ever imagine,
or it doesn't.
There's no middle ground for this,
I don't think.
This is squeaky bum the whole time.
But it's pretty cool to be a founder of a
business that's valued at
20 million. And that was a while ago,
so it's probably more than that.
Where JSA,
this is a lifestyle business that's tied
to me.
If I'm not at the top of that,
that doesn't exist.
Whereas up here,
if I'm not at the top of this,
it fails to exist.
With Nutonic,
although I do not plan on walking away
from it, I want to grow it the
whole way. When we go into retail,
the geniuses that sell it
to shops,
they don't even mention Chris Avi.
They just go straight in.
The amount of money
that I've had from Nutonic since we've
begun, zero.
So that's three revenue streams.
That one makes it, that one gobbles it up,
that one has kept me afloat.
But this building's paid for by that.
Next, podcast.
Bet you didn't even see
that as a business, did you?
So we've brought back the podcast this
year, off to a great start.
Want to see how much money it's made?
Because I'll show you.
There'll be links to all of these
businesses in the description.
The Problem With Podcast has made
£422.13 in AdSense because we only
turned the AdSense on the other day.
So as far as that as a business,
getting back into it, net
position at minus £180,000.
Because we've had the studio, the team,
we launched, equipment,
studio.
So whereas this looks really nice,
a lot of the money gets reinvested into
this.
That podcast will probably run at a loss
for about two years.
But the reason that the podcast to me
is such an important revenue stream
is just
the exposure.
So if you think the only thing
that I promote on the podcast
is James Smith Academy, Nutonic,
and the business mentorship.
So the podcast doesn't need to be a
profitable vessel.
It just needs to drive exposure to other
things in the ecosystem.
In two years' time,
that'll probably start making money.
But the only way that makes money
is through AdSense, which is not a lot, or
through the other businesses. But to me,
that is almost like a marketing
department.
Because content we make for this has to go
viral, has to go to a lead
magnet.
Content for this has to be creative,
I have to fly to America.
Content for this,
have to put loads of effort into YouTube.
But a podcast,
you put in an hour of your time,
you get an hour back.
It's the easiest return on investment for
content creation in the world.
You can get a million views from a video
of just talking to someone for an hour,
and you get to put ads in that, which
is crazy.
Another one would be JS Media. Currently
in a book cycle for book four.
I don't know the
exact amount,
but it's easily over £100,000 a book as an
advance.
Pretty sure the last one could have been
maybe 150 or 200.
I can't remember. So you get
that as an advance,
then you get royalties.
So every once in a while,
we get a check come through.
It'll be like, "Hey,
you've got £13,000." And where does
that go? To Luke.
So I, again, don't know about it.
But then when I say, "Hey, Luke,
where's my book
money?" He goes, "Oh,
do you not remember the studio you just
built?" And I'm like,
"Oh, sound." So we got a book, then
that book will come with events.
We'll do a tour off the back of it.
When we did the last book,
interestingly enough, there
was one point where we'd made more money
from the
events and the tour than we had from the
book, which was cool.
So another thing that goes into there
is bookings.
I did a talk last year, two-day event,
$150,000, which was
awesome. That was Australian,
so call it what?
80,000 US dollars for a weekend event,
which was nice.
So public speaking.
And then the thing about JS Media is,
let's say we
do live events.
The last live event we did, then funnel
people into the business mentorship.
The last live event we did,
we also had Nutonic on all the tables.
What else have we got? Oh, investments.
So investments.
First thing was,
I'm obviously a big fan of GLP-1s,
and I started TRT, and it's
changed my life. So invested into Manual.
Now being rebranded as VOI, which
is kind of annoying, but anyway.
So the way that works is,
as we get to grow the business,
we get to grow the
business.
There's an investment coming out into
another drinks business.
I'll keep that quite vague until we
announce.
And there's another investment into a
clothing brand, which we are going to
announce soon. Now,
the money I'm making over here
is also now going to go into
investments into other brands.
Because let's say, hypothetically,
this was a
beer brand.
We can now drink the beer on the podcast.
So we can now drink the beers after live
events.
And then for the clothing brand,
do you know what I do?
Wear the brand in podcasts.
Wear the brand in JSA events.
Wear the brand doing videos for business
mentorship.
We could do the brand with Nutonic,
and all the ecosystems start to
come together. How many is that? One, two,
three, four, five, six.
Probably it. Have I forgotten any? Hmm.
So that's pretty much how it's going to go
at the moment. Focus for 2026.
JSA, if the rev on
that continued at its current pace,
we'd be
happy. JS Media need to finish the book,
get the events going.
The book's not due till next year. Fine.
Podcast, I want to scale
that aggressively.
And the fact of the matter
is with the pod, the graph
is going to look like this.
Not a lot happens for ages,
and then suddenly it all just takes off.
Everyone seems to think like, "Oh,
you brought your pod back.
You're only getting 20,000,
30,000 downloads an episode." I'm like,
it goes like
that, and then eventually, boom.
I've seen it happen before.
Business mentorship.
Again,
if we coasted at 2 million US dollars a
year, it's not the end of the world,
but I would like to see
that start to hockey stick a bit again.
And Nutonic,
I'd like to get to 100 million pretty
soon.
And again,
Nutonic's going to work a bit like that.
We're going to move into retail very soon,
and the potential for that to just
explode is crazy.
Everything feeds into itself.
They're the six revenue streams.
That's how it works.
The lesson you can learn from this
is this.
Before I had any of this,
I just had a small, shitty face-to-face
business dishing out personal training
sessions for money.
The face-to-face became an online coaching
business.
The online coaching business then built
James Smith Media.
James Smith Media had the podcast before.
These coexisted for years.
I wasn't really doing that much.
Accrued enough knowledge to start a B2B
business.
All of this combined meant I brought the
podcast back.
And Nutonic, everything
that I did to build that brand then can
translate into that. So even
if I look at that as a business,
it's made me a few
mill, but nothing crazy.
All the effort and time
and energy I put into that, the
books, the events, the coaching business,
is now what's given me all of this.
And five years ago, it was just that.
So how big this whiteboard's going to get
over the next few years, I don't know.
The one thing that's grown all of this
is working on a personal brand.
And actually,
I've done a livestream webinar this week
where I explain all of the
things you need to know about building a
personal brand.
So if you've got a bit of time
and you want to get 10 years of knowledge
in just
over an hour and a bit,
then check out this video here.
It's going to give you all the information
you need.
If not,
check the links in the description to work
with me. Thank you very much.
Tune in. Bye-bye.